Gabriela Hernandez

Full Stack | Software Engineer | Front-End Developer
Fresno, California
Hernandez2Gab@gmail.com

(559) 305-3672 LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

Through my work as a Software Engineer and Front-End Developer, I strive to provide users with a concise, detailed, and aesthetically pleasing user experience with my web applications by utilizing emerging technologies and visual design.

SKILLS:

- **Programming Languages:** HTML and CSS, Javascript, Python
- Development Environment: Ubuntu, Command-Line, Visual Studio, Heroku
- Frameworks: Node.js, Express, Django, Bootstrap, React, Mongoose
- **Databases:** MongoDB, PostgreSQL
- **Methodologies:** Object-Oriented Programing, Wireframing

EXPERIENCE:

Software Engineering Immersive | General Assembly | Remote | March 2022 - June 2022

Attended a 12-week full-time immersive Software Engineering Bootcamp with more than 420 hours of hands-on development as well as an expert-led curriculum - including Computer Science, Web Development, and Front-End, and Back-End coding projects.

- <u>Connect Four:</u> Reconstructed a classic two-player turning it into a browser-based game using JavaScript algorithms and data structures.
 - JavaScript | CSS | HTML
- **POS-System:** A user-centric Point of Sale System by implementing MongoDB management and OAuth authentication for configuration and initialization.
 - Express | JavaScript | BootStrap | MongoDB |
- <u>Developers Meet Dating App</u>: Contributed to the development of a collaborative Python web application with AWS and Django Web Framework.
 - Python | BootStrap | Django | AWS | Git |
- NFT3 Social: Using NFTPorts' API, I developed a functional full-stack MERN application using the React web framework and synched it with MongoDB to store the user information and their preferred NFTs.
 - React | BootStrap | MongoDB | Node

Web3 | LearnWeb3.io | Remote | April 2022- Present

Participating in a self-paced educational program to learn about Web3, Smart Contracts, Decentralized Finance (Defi), NFT, Cryptocurrency, and Crypto Wallets. The curriculum consists of four levels of skills for advancing the development of and solving problems in innovative ways.

- Blockchain, Web3, mining, DeFi theory, and exchange.
- Acquired a basic understanding of programming languages such as React.js and Next.js.
- Practice developing Decentralized Apps (dApps) with Remix Workflow, Solidity, and the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM).
- Connect with others through social media -- Twitter, Discord, YouTube, and LinkedIn.

Photographer | Freelance | Various locations | August 2016 - Present

- Networking with several professional management companies to photograph live performances.
- Edits and processes post-production photographs using Adobe Suite- Photoshop, Lightroom.
- Organizes and arranges digital photographs to capture conceptual themes of photography.
- Work independently and collaboratively with driven local artists to build technical skills and develop creative strategies for projects and exhibitions.
- Communicate effectively with customers through the use of digital platforms.

Communications Intern | United Farm Workers Foundation | Remote | Jan 2020 - November 2021

- Created digital content surrounding Agriculture workers' rights, experiences, and protests throughout the United States.
- Translate media and materials to include the interaction of our Spanish-speaking audiences.
- Maintain social media posts, messages, and a positive presence on the United Farm Workers Facebook page.

Barista | Blue Bottle Coffee | San Francisco, California | November 2019 - October 2021

- Delivered excellent and friendly customer service.
- Promoted a safe, efficient and holistic work environment through continual learning, cultivating community and support.
- Upheld Blue Bottles standards of sustainability, quality, and knowledge of coffee.
- The ability to adapt to a fast-paced environment and fluctuating circumstances with a positive attitude

EDUCATION:

Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp | General Assembly | Remote | March 2022 - June 2022

B.A Concentration: Art | San Francisco State University | San Francisco, California | May 2021

A.A Studio Art | Reedley College | Reedley, California | May 2018